<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title></title>
    <link href="https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link href="https://PhilipMetzger.github.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>On three years in the Jujutsu project</title>
        <published>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/blog/jj-year-three/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/blog/jj-year-three/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intended Audience:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; The people from the Jujutsu Discord and random 
bypassers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note-container&quot;&gt;
  
    &lt;div class=&quot;note-header&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;div class=&quot;note-icon&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Disclaimer&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

        &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
      
    &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;note-content&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The year I&#x27;m talking about is from &lt;br&gt;
2024.11.03 - 2025.11.03, this also has an alternative title &lt;br&gt;
&#x27;Three years of whatever this is&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

    &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
  
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-happened-in-the-project&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-happened-in-the-project&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-happened-in-the-project&quot;&gt;What happened in the project.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this year the project moved from &lt;code&gt;martinvonz&#x2F;jj&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to the Alphabet 
suborganization &lt;code&gt;jj-vcs&#x2F;jj&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; which also led to the logo change away from the 
Jujube, the previous name of the project, to the two blue jays which were drawn
by J.J and got its governance with the first set of Maintainers. We also choose 
to standardize the &lt;code&gt;change-id:&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; header in the Git object with both GitButler and
Gerrit. Which Martin then brought up in the Git mailing list.
The standardization of the &lt;code&gt;change-id&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; header also brought many 
discussions about the UX of divergence in the project which has improved a bit.
These discussions aren&#x27;t done yet since it requires the users to understand
that divergence is not a &amp;quot;failure&amp;quot; state and isn&#x27;t as harmful as conflicts.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CLA also was a really tiring hot issue this year, in which better 
communication definitely would&#x27;ve helped.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;ersc.io&quot;&gt;East River Source Control&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; came out of hiding which makes the 
project have three interested parties, Google, ERSC and Open-Source users.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project also had a new community leader step up as another one stepped
down.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There also was the first convention for the project in Sunnyvale 
California named &amp;quot;JJ-Con&amp;quot;, which was colocated with Git Merge 2025. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-year&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#my-year&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: my-year&quot;&gt;My year&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-bad-start-until-the-summer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-bad-start-until-the-summer&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-bad-start-until-the-summer&quot;&gt;A bad start until the summer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly my year wasn&#x27;t great, since I choose to add my name to the 
potential &amp;quot;Maintainer&amp;quot; list where I personally already thought that it was 
unlikely for me to get added (like a 0.01% chance). Since I was the only person
who wasn&#x27;t chosen it didn&#x27;t feel great to hear about it on the Jan 1st post 
without receiving a message beforehand. I also stepped into a discussion with
Drew Devault because it was eerily similar to what I&#x27;d do or already did in 
the past. While I also had some plans to give the
project docs a better structure, it never happened because I lost my job in 
February. At the same time I also asked someone for their prototype of 
integrating a scripting language with &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; so I could work on it. I also 
continued my work on the Topics design doc before burning out on it. At various
points early in the year, I&#x27;ve had the feeling of my opinion not being seen 
which resulted in the horrible message I sent in Spring.
I think this could&#x27;ve been entirely prevented by the project having active
moderation, not just people sitting on the sideline. While the conflict 
resolution was quite fast, it affected me negatively for longer which 
obviously isn&#x27;t great&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;. It almost resulted in me quitting the project 
entirely. The whole situation forced me to recognize what I achieved in the 
project to get myself back on my feet, it also took some time until I was 
comfortable expressing myself in the Discord again&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;. This year I lost 
multiple nights of sleep to the project, by just having my name mentioned in 
certain ways and I had various moments where I was questioning my motivations 
in the project, since it had such negative effects on me. In July I was back to 
&amp;quot;normal&amp;quot;, if there&#x27;s such a thing. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;jj-con-and-git-merge&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#jj-con-and-git-merge&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: jj-con-and-git-merge&quot;&gt;JJ-Con and Git Merge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when the CFP for JJ-Con went up in July, I just decided to write a cool 
title for a side-project I wanted to discuss anyway. I was very baffled to see 
that it was the most liked talked during the first three days of voting and it 
was even stranger to me that it held its top five position which allowed me to 
hold the talk&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#3&quot;&gt;3&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;. JJ-Con and the all the events around it were a bunch of 
firsts for me, I gave a &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;QPp_o3CMJlY?si=fyUkn1ZVw_ONQ0VT&quot;&gt;technical talk&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, held a &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;youtu.be&#x2F;JWEFkZr7TIc?si=_kjdXVfyCnqIepgg&quot;&gt;discussion&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and 
upon the suggestion of Manish held a unconference session which was related to
the current governance. Also Git Merge was smaller than I expected and quite 
nice. I also got to talk to the Sapling developers which were interested in 
the scripting language I proposed for &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. There I also was asked if I were 
interested in  working in Source Control which was quite interesting&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#4&quot;&gt;4&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;. 
It also was the first time I&#x27;ve heard that I stand up for the community, which
never crossed my mind since I only represent myself and try my best to consider
what the community wants.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To my surprise I even could attend the Git contributor summit which was an
interesting experience of its own where I tried to push the change-id header
discussion a bit further.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;my-pain-points-with-the-current-governance&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#my-pain-points-with-the-current-governance&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: my-pain-points-with-the-current-governance&quot;&gt;My pain points with the current Governance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current governance is doing its job poorly with these points for me:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It fails to be any kind of organization, instead it&#x27;s a bunch of 
individuals.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There&#x27;s still not any kind of leadership, be it in a social or technical
manner. Deferring to the community is not leadership for people which 
should deem themselves as the &amp;quot;core project&amp;quot;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is not transparent at all with its decision making with all the leading 
steps upon its creation.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It also immediately failed to write down the &lt;em&gt;actual job&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; of a Maintainer
presenting some vague ideas which only the people involved in the temporary
Governance understand (this excludes a high amount of the community). &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It on one hand wants to steer the technical and organizational direction 
of the project while it hasn&#x27;t proven it being capable of any of these.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also don&#x27;t find it good at all that a majority of the Maintainers can&#x27;t take
the time necessary for the project only retaining their voting position, if it
comes to that. I mean a Maintainer should be active in the project and 
concerned about its future and not constantly complain about the length of the
PR queue, since they&#x27;re responsible for the development speed of the project.
I also find it bad capacity planning to make 2&#x2F;N maintainers responsible for 
a vast majority of code-reviews, since it will create a single point of failure
when one of them has to disappear for internal needs at times. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the above make my opinion of the Governance lacking, I mean it is OK 
but it definitely could improve and make their position clearer. If I were 
Google I&#x27;d wait another year to see how it improves and what pans out.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;closing&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#closing&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: closing&quot;&gt;Closing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point it has been three years since I joined the project wanting to 
write &lt;code&gt;jj run&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. During this time I&#x27;ve answered &lt;em&gt;many&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; questions about the 
project, tried to implement some processes for it and even had a plan on how a 
native future could look. I even recognized that the project has no 
leadership figure and thus drove some decisions even though I was asked to 
step back from this. At this point I&#x27;ve worn many hats, some of them making 
time for own code contributions  harder, this by sometimes shielding people 
from questions and otherwise. I want to write code too. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also seems that multiple people in the project think that I&#x27;m a Googler 
working on this full-time as a lead, which is both an insult and a compliment.
I have my own reasons to be here, such as making the project a success and 
having an actual Jujutsu-native future, not just as a better Git client. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have thought about enabling GitHub sponsors to give the community a 
way of sponsoring my presence on the project but I find that soliticing money
for something I already do extremely hard. Maybe someone could convince me that
it is a good idea, since my involvement currently doesn&#x27;t pay for my rent. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also could try to get into the Maintainer position next year but I doubt it
will happen even though it would validate all my efforts across the years for 
the project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I&#x27;ve also have become very interested in making Meta a third 
party involved in the project since someone talked about their use-case in 
the Discord and I always said that I want to write a &lt;code&gt;jj on EdenFS&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. But
that will be in a separate article and which I promised to at least one person.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last such post ended with my plans for next year, but since I was unable to
implement them this year, I&#x27;ll just keep on working on my publicly known
projects, which means at some point pulling out the &lt;code&gt;Topics&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; design doc out of
the freezer again. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I should have received a warning per CoC but that didn&#x27;t really happen.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;2&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#x27;t really feel safe for two weeks. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;3&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&#x27;ve held presentations, this was the first time I ever gave a
technical talk in front of a large crowd.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;4&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I obviously would like to, but I find it unlikely that I receive a job 
offer from Google or Meta.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Reflecting on two years on the Jujutsu Project</title>
        <published>2024-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/blog/reflection-year-two-jj/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/blog/reflection-year-two-jj/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audience:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; The people from the &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.gg&#x2F;dkmfj3aGQN&quot;&gt;Jujutsu Discord&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and random bypassers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;note-container&quot;&gt;
  
    &lt;div class=&quot;note-header&quot;&gt;
      
        &lt;div class=&quot;note-icon&quot;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Disclaimer&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

        &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
      
    &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;note-content&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;This is my page, so I&#x27;m allowed to liberally critize myself.&lt;br&gt;
If you disagree with that feel free to keep it to yourself. &lt;b&gt;It is my own choice.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;

    &lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
  
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has grown by a sizeable amount and as such also the Discord. While
this makes it less comfortable to me, it shows that this is the right approach
to a new VCS. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it was a strange year for me in the project, as judging by 
the &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;jj-vcs.github.io&#x2F;jj&#x2F;latest&#x2F;testimonials&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Testimonials&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; page which I added to the docs made me a &amp;quot;Developer&amp;quot;
(thankfully no Maintainer yet).
I see myself as a fine technical contributor, but my social skills sometimes 
are not the best and mixing that with strong opinions is a dangerous concoction.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-bad-aka-making-mistakes&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-bad-aka-making-mistakes&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-bad-aka-making-mistakes&quot;&gt;The Bad (aka making mistakes)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During early Spring this year, I made some mistakes and was a undoubtely 
a bad &lt;em&gt;contributor&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to the project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It started with my &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;jj-vcs&#x2F;jj&#x2F;pull&#x2F;2842#issuecomment-1979068782&quot;&gt;giant fuckup&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;. And as I believe actions should 
have consequences, this led to a very personal offer to  @martinvonz 
and the formation of a &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;jj-vcs&#x2F;jj&#x2F;discussions&#x2F;3877&quot;&gt;Governance structure&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then the whole &lt;code&gt;prev&#x2F;next&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; debacle also wasn&#x27;t great to continue that 
streak, where once again my &lt;em&gt;strong&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; words did not help anyone. 
I believe that my reactions there were &lt;em&gt;toxic&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And to top it off, the whole hook discussion also strained me heavily. Here
I am thankful for the private conversation I had with Matt (@msta).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of these interactions were not beneficial to me, or my mental state
which led to the reoccurring thought of just resigning from the project. While
this solves the immediate issue, it doesn&#x27;t remove my interest in project 
itself and I think keeping me around as a person with some strong opinions 
can help the project grow further. And as I owe everyone the &lt;code&gt;jj run&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; 
implementation, it is hard to disappear into shadows. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After taking a healthy break this summer, my attitude finally improved towards
the project and I got my motivation back to work on &lt;code&gt;jj&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-good&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-good&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-good&quot;&gt;The Good&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was motivated to continue my work on &lt;code&gt;run&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; after taking a break. 
Hopefully it is in a MVP state now. Then Matt (@msta) started the initial work
on &lt;code&gt;jj api&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; which won&#x27;t be finished any time soon, as it will need to grow
with the project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then we also went ahead and &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;jj-vcs&#x2F;jj&#x2F;pull&#x2F;4341&quot;&gt;renamed Jujutsu&#x27;s branches to bookmarks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, 
which opens the path for &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;jj-vcs&#x2F;jj&#x2F;issues&#x2F;3402&quot;&gt;Topics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and solidifies it as our first term 
(although a similarily named but different mechanism exists for Mercurial).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward-in-the-project&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#looking-forward-in-the-project&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: looking-forward-in-the-project&quot;&gt;Looking forward in the Project&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My personal goal for the next year is to finish &lt;code&gt;jj run&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and give others 
some room with it, I think both @hooper and @arxanas can improve it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The things I really want to get in for next year is &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;jj-vcs&#x2F;jj&#x2F;issues&#x2F;3402&quot;&gt;Topics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, where I also 
was heavily involved and get the ball rolling on interchanging Change-IDs in
the Git protocol and the start of some kind of native repository&#x2F;server to 
begin modeling the world from Jujutsu&#x27;s eyes, as importing terms from Git never 
helped the project. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also want the more powerful aliases, so we can deprecate &lt;code&gt;jj commit&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and make
it a configurable alias for those who want to stick to the 30 years of VCS 
history.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the docs side, I still want to completly restructure them when Steve 
Klabnik&#x27;s tutorial lands. As they&#x27;re a bit incoherent.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#conclusion&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the year of communication failure, both in the project and at 
&lt;code&gt;$WORK&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, where my frustration from work clearly affected my behavior in the 
project, which definitely wasn&#x27;t what I wanted. I also will stick around for 
now, although always keeping a self-ban in mind.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve also really tried to improve on my communication which is something I 
intend to keep up for next year (I expect occassional relapses, but such is 
life). &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macro-expanded &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;jj-vcs&#x2F;jj&#x2F;pull&#x2F;3218#pullrequestreview-1917415818&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A short reflection upon almost a Year of Jujutsu usage</title>
        <published>2024-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2024-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/blog/a-year-jujutsu-usage/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/blog/a-year-jujutsu-usage/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;(Note: This post was originally a &lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.com&#x2F;channels&#x2F;968932220549103686&#x2F;968932220549103689&#x2F;1169702852986417172&quot;&gt;Discord message&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in the 
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.gg&#x2F;dkmfj3aGQN&quot;&gt;Jujutsu Discord&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Sidenote: It was primarily used for contributing here and personal projects)&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
As a pretty stupid user of Git, I really like all the changes and it being less
footgunny. I really like revsets, they make the log a really useful tool. Some 
features I&#x27;m missing &lt;code&gt;jj run&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; (the author should really get to it)&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-reference&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;, blame, 
&lt;code&gt;jj sync&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;jj submit&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and change detection. As I&#x27;ve written a bunch of 
documentation, I think there should be some sort of polish for the tutorial as 
quite a lot has changed and I think we should provide some guides like: 
&lt;em&gt;What are  some similar workflows to &#x27;git add -p&#x27;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; that could be used in a 
Codelab. And I really enjoy contributing here and meeting Martin and Ilya was
cool.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnote-definition&quot; id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-definition-label&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;sup&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m calling myself out, if that is not &lt;em&gt;obvious&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>A list of links</title>
        <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/links/useful/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/links/useful/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;here-is-a-incomplete-list-of-creators-or-companies-with-good-content&quot;&gt;Here is a incomplete list of creators or companies with good content&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;blogs-i-like&quot;&gt;Blogs I like&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;rachelbythebay.com&#x2F;w&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Rachel&#x27;s Blog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is full of realistic cynicism. 
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;danluu.com&quot;&gt;Dan Luu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, is always insightful. 
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;jvns.ca&quot;&gt;Julia Evans&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, her short exploratory blogs helped me.
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;randomascii.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;Bruce Dawson&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, he always shows interesting perf problems.
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;matklad.github.io&quot;&gt;Matklad&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, writes succinct articles about Rust and Zig.
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;faultlore.com&#x2F;blah&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Gankra&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, on point with the programming language analysis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;articles-i-like&quot;&gt;Articles I like&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- Highlighted articles get their own sections, either using the Author&#x27;s or 
the companies name. --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section is not ordered in any way, so please search for either the 
Author&#x27;s name, the company name or the respective paper or blog post. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;rachelbythebay&quot;&gt;Rachelbythebay&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably my favorite series so far, how releasing stuff to a massive fleet 
broke stuff.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;rachelbythebay.com&#x2F;w&#x2F;2020&#x2F;04&#x2F;23&#x2F;rel&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Releasing software to the fleet far too quickly broke stuff&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;rachelbythebay.com&#x2F;w&#x2F;2020&#x2F;04&#x2F;25&#x2F;rel&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Moving fleet software releases to a massively sharded scheme&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;rachelbythebay.com&#x2F;w&#x2F;2020&#x2F;04&#x2F;29&#x2F;rel&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Rolling out the &amp;quot;push train&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some other gems from her&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;rachelbythebay.com&#x2F;w&#x2F;2013&#x2F;02&#x2F;02&#x2F;steps&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Replacing &amp;quot;scripter mentality&amp;quot; code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;rachelbythebay.com&#x2F;w&#x2F;2013&#x2F;02&#x2F;03&#x2F;quorum&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Reaching a quorum of machines&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
[Looking for the duct tape]&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And a special shoutout to the random numbers series&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;fly-io&quot;&gt;Fly.io&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have excellent explanations of what actually happens under the hood.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fly.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;the-5-hour-content-delivery-network&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The 5-hour CDN&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, by Kurt Mackey
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fly.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;docker-without-docker&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Docker without Docker&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, by Thomas Ptaecek
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fly.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;sandboxing-and-workload-isolation&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Sandboxing and Workload isolation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, by Thomas Ptacek
[Carving the Scheduler Out of the Orchestrator], by Thomas Ptacek
[Making Machines move], by Thomas Ptacek
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fly.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;api-tokens-a-tedious-survey&#x2F;&quot;&gt;API Tokens: A tedious Survey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, by Thomas Ptacek
[Macaroons, ???], by Thomas Ptacek&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole SQLite series is also outstanding, as someone who spent a 
loooooooong time looking at the source code.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fly.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;sqlite-internals-btree&#x2F;&quot;&gt;SQLite Internals: Pages &amp;amp; B-trees&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fly.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;sqlite-internals-rollback-journal&#x2F;&quot;&gt;How SQLite Helps You Do ACID&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fly.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;sqlite-internals-rollback-journal&#x2F;&quot;&gt;How SQLite Scales Read Concurrency&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;fly.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;sqlite-internals-rollback-journal&#x2F;&quot;&gt;How the SQLite Virtual Machine Works&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, by Ben Johnson&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloudflare&quot;&gt;Cloudflare&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;other&quot;&gt;Other&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;!-- The format is Article, $Author --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Build Systems], by Name
[Turing incomplete languages], by Neil Mitchell
[Kubernetes is our generations Multics], by Andy Chu
[I want off Mr. Golangs Wild Ride], by Amos Wenger
[Other Golang Flame Article], by Amos Wenger
[The Success and Failure of Ninja], by Evan Martin
[Futures, Generators Series], by WithoutBoats
[Static Languages Complexity] by Hirrolot
[Rust Async Sucks] by Hirrolot.
&lt;a rel=&quot;noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;yosefk.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;people-can-read-their-managers-mind.html&quot;&gt;People can read their manager&#x27;s mind&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by Yossi Kreini
[Our Dependency Problem], by Russ Cox&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-here-is-a-incomplete-list-of-my-favorite-talks&quot;&gt;And here is a incomplete list of my favorite talks&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;!-- The format is Title, Speakers --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[What is C++], Chandler Carruth and Titus Winters 
[What are Languages], Titus Winters
[Using C++ as a live at Head Language], Titus Winters
[LLVM Substrates], Nicolai Hähnle
[What did my Compiler do for me today], Matt Godbolt
[Using C++ in three ways], Matt Godbolt&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- People --&gt;
&lt;!-- Individual Blog posts --&gt;
&lt;!-- sorted by Author&#x2F;Company name --&gt;
&lt;!-- Hirrolot --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Why static Languages suffer from complexicity]: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;!-- Fasterthanlime --&gt;
&lt;!-- Fly.io --&gt;
&lt;!-- Rachelbythebay --&gt;
&lt;!-- Russ Cox --&gt;
&lt;!-- Withoutboats --&gt;
&lt;!-- Yossi Kreinin --&gt;
&lt;!-- Papers --&gt;
&lt;!-- Talks --&gt;
&lt;!-- sorted by year, alphabetically --&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hello World</title>
        <published>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2023-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        <author>
          <name>Unknown</name>
        </author>
        <link rel="alternate" href="https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/blog/hello-world/" type="text/html"/>
        <id>https://PhilipMetzger.github.io/blog/hello-world/</id>
        
        <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello from my Blog. Let&#x27;s see what happens. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
